<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on </title>
    <link>https://r-mas.github.io/categories/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://r-mas.github.io/categories/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Market Price Data using Bloomberg API</title>
      <link>https://r-mas.github.io/post/scraping-market-price-data-using-bloomberg-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r-mas.github.io/post/scraping-market-price-data-using-bloomberg-api/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is a soft update to my previous post on Exploring UITFs in the Philippines. One limitation of that study is that the historical prices used were limited to the past 12 months only. In this post, I’m going to share how to scrape up to 5 years worth of historical prices from Bloomberg.com.
 Bloomberg “bulk-time-series” API I owe a big thanks to this wonderful article on finding the API by Greg Reda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring UITFs in the Philippines</title>
      <link>https://r-mas.github.io/post/exploring-uitfs-in-the-philippines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r-mas.github.io/post/exploring-uitfs-in-the-philippines/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is the second part of a series of posts about Unit Investment Trust Funds or UITFs in the Philippines. In this post, I’ll dive into the dataset produced in the previous post, looking to answer more specific questions such as:
What are the available UITFs in the Philippines? Which banks offer them? What are the different types of UITFs? What are the differences between each type?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Web Data on UITFs Using R</title>
      <link>https://r-mas.github.io/post/scraping-web-data-on-uitfs-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r-mas.github.io/post/scraping-web-data-on-uitfs-using-r/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is an example of scraping the web for specific data we would like to have for analysis. In this example, I’m going to gather data on UITFs in the Philippines. UITFs or Unit Investment Trust Funds are a type of pooled funds, similar but still somewhat different to mutual funds.
Specific goals for this activity are:
Create a complete list of all active UITFs in the Philippines Gather information about all UITFs Answer the simple question: Which is the best performing UITF?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>